{
    "id": "bf20a56e1e974b3c9a699eca275c867d",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Janet …………………………… in the countryside.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about permanent situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "live",
                "is living"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………… feeding cats and dogs.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about people's likes, dislikes, habits, routines etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "enjoy",
                "enjoys",
                "is enjoying"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Call me the moment you …………………………… the results.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "gets",
                "will get"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If only you hadn’t called the police, everything ………………………………….. all right.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I ……………………….. that car serviced.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would + bare infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "would get",
                "would have got"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "‘What are you doing?’ ‘I ………………………….. a bath.’",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about an ongoing action or situation. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "am having"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………………. here for twenty years by next Christmas.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will be living",
                "will have been living",
                "would be living"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. them since Monday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't see",
                "haven't seen",
                "hadn't seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………….. since morning and I am getting tired.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "am working",
                "have been working",
                "was working"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They ……………………………. to their native place next week.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about preplanned future events. ",
            "answers": [
                "move",
                "are moving",
                "will move"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if I ……………………………. her key.",
            "description": "A present perfect in the direct question becomes past perfect in the reported question. ",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "have seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………………….. a shelter for sick and abandoned dogs and cats.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "runs",
                "is running",
                "run"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}